Keith Deuser

Lawrenceville, GA 30044 • 678-438-5845 • <u>keithdeu@gatech.edu</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/keith-deuser</u> • <u>https://keithdeu.github.io/</u>

SKILLS

Software: Excel, Jupyter Notebooks, SQL Server (SSMS), Tableau, Power BI, Microsoft Word,

Outlook, ArcGIS Pro

Programming: Python, SQL, R

Data Analysis: Data cleaning, advanced sorting and filtering, reports forecasting, statistical analysis, data

mining, visualizing trends, and creating dashboards. Exposure to logistics, finance,

marketing, and business analysis via education.

Machine Learning: Experience with forecasting, classification, clustering, and regression analysis

Mathematics: Probability and Statistics, Calculus, and Linear Algebra

Management: Successfully led a team of independent contractors at Craftsmen Contractors after sales

increased by 50% in 2016-2018. Detail-oriented with strong problem solving skills.

Communication: creating reports for stakeholders via Excel and/or Word, customer service background,

strong written and verbal communication, conflict resolution

Certifications: Google Data Analytics Specialization, Database Foundations: Data Structures, Python 3

Programming Specialization, Managing and Analyzing Data in Excel, MySQL, Tableau

Essential Training

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Atlanta, GA

2022 - Present

- Master of Science, Analytics
- Completed Coursework: Computing for Data Analysis, Introduction to Analytics Modeling, Business Fundamentals for Analytics, Simulation for Engineering and Science

GEORGIA STATE UNIVERSITY, Atlanta, GA

2008 - 2012

• Bachelor of Science, Music

EXPERIENCE

MYERS & STAUFFER, Atlanta, GA

02/2023 - 03/2024

Data Analyst

- Utilize SQL, Python, Power BI, and Excel for data analysis projects and creating reports.
- Utilize Python in ArcGIS Pro for automating geospatial, calculating the distance of healthcare members to closest providers
- Create Python scripts which automate processes such as importing data from SQL databases, explore/clean/manipulate data, export results back to SQL or Excel for further reporting/analysis, scrape data from PDFs and file directories
- Compare similar datasets utilizing SQL (primarily Joins) and Excel to find key differences and similarities
- Review and clean (if needed) state submitted large healthcare datasets
- Update and/or create complex SQL scripts and stored procedures

PESTBAN, Suwanee, GA

02/2019 - 02/2023

Accounts Receivable Administrator / Finance Department

- Automate 50+ excel reports per month using Python
- Successfully manage database of up to 900+ accounts
- Responsible for \$4600, on average, in revenue per week for company
- Decrease the number of delinquent accounts by 40%
- Make outbound and receive inbound calls to assist customers with accounts

CRAFTSMEN CONTRACTORS, Buford, GA

2014 - 2018

Production Manager

- Managed over \$600,000 monthly from point of sale to completion of work and payment
- Maintained regular communication with 100+ clients and managed customer expectations to achieve positive experience from point of sale to payment
- Managed 5000 sq ft warehouse and incoming shipments of windows, siding, roofing, and insulation materials
- Managed scheduling and payment of contractors upon completion of work for over 15+ contractors

TOWN CENTER MUSIC AND GWINNETT SCHOOL OF MUSIC, Suwanee, GA 2012 – 2015 Guitar Instructor

- Taught 60+ students of all ages, skill levels, and interests including classical, jazz, rock, pop
- Developed curriculum for each student, based on individual needs and interests
- Maintained a fun learning environment combined with a growth mindset

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

PANDEMIC FLU SPREAD SIMULATION

11/2023

Using Python and Excel to Simulate Small-Scale Flu Spread

• Utilized Python Pandas and Numpy modules to simulate a flu outbreak within a classroom of students. Analyze results using Pandas and Excel

DATA SCIENCE VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE PROGRAM

01/2023

Using Sentiment Analysis and K Nearest Neighbor Model on Airline Data

• Scraped the web of British Airways yelp review data, and performed sentiment analysis using python, along with predicting whether or not a customer booked a flight using K Nearest Neighbor model

ACCENTURE VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE PROGRAM PARTICIPANT

01/2023

Data Analytics and Visualization Virtual Experience

 Completed analysis and visualization for Social Buzz, a social media platform, to help them expand and grow their data infrastructure, gain valuable data insights, and help guide and expand their overall business

TATA VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE PROGRAM PARTICIPANT

12/2022

Data Visualization: Empowering Business with Effective Insights

• Completed analysis of online retail data using Excel and Power BI, including cleaning the dataset and ensuring data integrity, and generated visualizations in Power BI to gain marketing and business insights

COMPUTING FOR DATA ANALYSIS

11/2022

Generating Chorales and Ranking Chords with Python

 Wrote Python program in Jupyter Notebooks that generates chorales based on training set of 228 Bach chorales. Performed Markov chain analysis to rank chords